A Finding Aid to the George Tooker Papers, circa 1851-2010, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
George Tooker papers
circa 1851-2010
Archives of American Art
Tooker, George, 1920-2011
AAA.tookgeor
Archival Resource Key
5.1 Linear feet
The papers of painter George Tooker measure 5.1 linear feet and date from circa 1851 to 2010. The papers document Tooker's personal and professional life through biographical material, correspondence, project files, gallery files, exhibition files, printed material, artwork and one sketchbook, and numerous photographs, including some taken by noted photographer George Platt Lynes.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 8 series.
Missing Title
Series 1: Biographical Material, circa 1920-2005 (0.7 linear feet; Boxes 1, 5)
Series 2: Correspondence, circa 1932-2010 (1.2 linear feet; Boxes 1-2, Oversize 7)
Series 3: Project Files, circa 1935-1968 (0.3 linear feet; Boxes 2-3, 6)
Series 4: Gallery Records, circa 1960-2009 (0.3 linear feet; Box 3)
Series 5: Exhibition Files, circa 1967-2009 (0.3 linear feet; Boxes 1, 3)
Series 6: Printed Material, circa 1851-2010 (0.5 linear feet; Boxes 3, 5)
Series 7: Artwork and Sketchbook, circa 1932-2009 (0.7 linear feet; Boxes 3, 5, 8)
Series 8: Photographs, circa 1900-2010 (1.1 linear feet; Boxes 4-5, 8)
Biographical / Historical
George Tooker (1920-2011) was a painter based in Hartland, Vermont and New York, New York. Tooker was born in Brooklyn, New York on August 5, 1920 to George Clair Tooker and Angela Montejo Roura. He graduated from preparatory school at Phillips Academy, Andover in 1938 and received a Bachelor of Arts in English from Harvard University in 1942. Tooker studied drawing and painting under Reginald Marsh, Kenneth Hayes Miller, and Harry Sternberg at the Art Students' League from circa 1944 to 1945.
Tooker became acquainted with American painter Paul Cadmus while studying at the Art Students' League. Cadmus introduced Tooker to a circle of artists and writers living and working in New York and Europe in the mid to late 1940s that included George Platt Lynes, Jared and Margaret French, Monroe Wheeler, Glenway Westcott, and Lincoln and Fidelma Kirstein. He lived and worked with his partner and fellow artist William Christopher in New York City and later Hartland, VT.
In 1953, Tooker was commissioned by writer and philanthropist Lincoln Kirstein to design the sets and costumes for The Saint of Bleecker Street, an opera by Gian-Carlo Menotti. In 1966, the Wasemquia Charitable Trust sponsored the Vestris Prize for Choreography in cooperation with the Boston Ballet Company and Tooker was invited by trustee Henry H. Crapo to participate on the Committee of Judges for the Vestris Prize. In 1968, NASA commissioned Tooker to produce drawings and one painting documenting the development of spacecraft at the Goddard Space Flight Center located in Greenbelt, Maryland.
Tooker's paintings are found in numerous art museums and galleries including the Whitney Museum of Art, Metropolitan Museum of Art, Museum of Modern Art, DC Moore Gallery, Robert Isaacson Gallery, and the Venice Biennale. In 1968, Tooker's paintings were featured in the art magazine, Avant-Garde.
Conditions Governing Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C., Research Center. Contact Reference Services for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
George Tooker donated his papers to the Archives of American Art in 1973. A subsequent addition was donated in 2018 by Aaron Watkins, the executor to George Tooker's estate.
Scope and Contents
The papers of painter George Tooker measure 5.1 linear feet and date from circa 1851 to 2010. The papers document Tooker's personal and professional life through biographical material, correspondence, project files, gallery files, exhibition files, printed material, artwork and one sketchbook, and numerous photographs, including some taken by noted photographer George Platt Lynes.
Biographical material consists of membership and travel documents, writings on and by Tooker on his circle, an address book, resume, and papers regarding Tooker's education. Also included are biographical material related to Tooker's partner William Christopher who passed in 1973. A 1978 interview with Vermont Public radio on two sound reels is also featured.
Correspondence is with friends, colleagues, and organizations. Correspondents include Isabel Bishop, Paul Cadmus, Walter Bachinski, William Christopher, Otto Dix, Jared and Margaret French, Ralph Ginzburg, Xavier Gonzalez, Robert Isaacson, Edward Laning, Lincoln Kirstein, Lee Nordness, Bernard Perlin, Joan Peterson, Theodore Stamos, Bridget Tichenor, and others. Also included are family correspondence and correspondence regarding the Estate of William Christopher.
Project files document Tooker's commissions including the set and costume design for Gian-Carlo Menotti's opera The Saint of Bleecker Street and Tooker's participation in the selection of candidates for the Vestris Prize for Choreography. Files contain correspondence, business documents, printed ephemera, sketches, photographs, three volumes of vocal scores, and textile samples.
Gallery records include business correspondence and consignments with various key galleries in Tooker's career spanning the 1960s to the end of his career including D.C. Moore Gallery, Marisa Del Re Gallery, and Durlacher Bros..
Exhibition records include documents regarding the organization of several select exhibitions in Tooker's career incuding an early retrospective at the Fine Arts Museums of San Francisco (1974) and a later traveling retrospective from 2008-2009.
Printed material consists of invitations, press releases, news clippings and exhibition catalogs documenting the careers of both George Tooker and William Christopher.
Artwork includes numerous sketchbooks, loose drawings, and sketches from Tooker's studies at the Art Students' League in the mid 1940s, in addition to an early ex-libris print created by Tooker in his youth. Also included is a sketchbook by William Christopher, as well as a study for the work The Subway, in the collection of the Whitney Museum of American Art.
Photographic materials depict Tooker's family life as well as his early artistic collaborations depicted in a number of black and white photographs taken by George Platt Lynes and PaJaMa in the mid to late 1940s. A majority of the photographs depict artists and friends, among them: George Tooker and his companion William Christopher, Paul Cadmus, Jared and Margaret French, Lincoln and Fidelma Kirstein, Glenway Wescott, Monroe Wheeler, and Bridget Tichenor. Other photographs are of Tooker building his home, gardening, and working in his studio in Hartland, Vermont. Also included are installation views from the exhibition Painting in the United States (1949) at the Carnegie Institute in Pennsylvania. There are also a fair amount of photographs, transparencies, slides and negatives documenting artwork from both the studios of George Tooker and his late partner William Christopher.
Related Materials
Available in the Archives of American Art is an oral history interview with George Tooker conducted in 1966 by Grace G. Alexander for radio station WNYC, New York City.
Materials related to the George Tooker papers can be found the William Christopher papers at the Archives of American Art.
Existence and Location of Copies
Portions of the collection are available on 35 mm microfilm reels 678-679 and 692 at the Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan.Researchers should note that the arrangement of the material described in the container inventory does not reflect the arrangement of the collection on microfilm.
Painters -- Vermont; Sketchbooks; Drawings; Printmakers -- Vermont; Scrapbooks; Bachinski, Walter; Bishop, Isabel, 1902-1988; Cadmus, Paul, 1904-1999; Christopher, William R, 1924-1973; Kirstein, Lincoln, 1907-; Dix, Otto, 1891-1969; Peterson, Joan, 1933-; Gonzalez, Xavier, 1898-1993; Kirstein, Fidelma; Lynes, George Platt, 1907-1955; Laning, Edward, 1906-1981; Isaacson, Robert; Ginzburg, Ralph; Stamos, Theodoros, 1922-1997; French, Margaret; Nordness, Lee; French, Jared, 1905-1988; Wheeler, Monroe, 1899-; Wescott, Glenway, 1901-; Perlin, Bernard, 1918-
- Biographical Material, circa 1920-2005; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 0.7 Linear feet Boxes 1, 5
  Scope and Contents
  Biographical material consists of membership and travel documents, writings on and by Tooker on his circle, an address book, resume, and papers regarding Tooker's education. Also included are biographical material related to Tooker's partner William Christopher who passed in 1973. A 1978 interview with Vermont Public radio on two sound reels is also featured.
  - Baby Book, 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - High School Diploma, Phillips Academy, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Educational Documents, 1938, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - U.S. Marine Corps Service Documents, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - U.S. Passports, 1949-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - VT Drivers License, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Résumé, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Membership Documents, 1932, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Museum Memberships, circa 1970s-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Affidavit of George C. Tooker Jr. for sponsorship of Jose Perez visit to U.S., 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Land Survey for Brookhaven, Suffolk Co., NY, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Essay on George Tooker by Robert Isaacson, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Biographical Sketch for George Tooker, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Poems dedicated to George Tooker, 1980, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Lecture Typescript on George Tooker, circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Tribute to Paul Cadmus by George Tooker, American Academy of Arts and Letters (Nov. 14, 2000), Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Statement on George Tooker by Paul Cadmus "The Proper Study of Mankind is Man", 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "On Being an Artist" by Gloria Brancaleoni, circa 1970s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Journal, Garden Notes, circa 1978-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Journal, Addresses, Recipes, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Address Book, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Holy Bible, circa 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Journal of William Christopher, Europe, circa 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Journal of William Christopher, circa 1971-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Journal of William Christopher, Artwork Inventory, Photography Log, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - William Christopher, U.S. Navy Certificate of Discharge, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - William Christopher Résumé, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Interview of G. Tooker by Frank Anthony for Vermont Public Radio, Legendry Program, 1978; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound tape reels; Includes 2 sound reels and one letter (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Governor's Award for Excellence in the Arts, VT, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - National Medal of the Arts, Letter and Medal, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - National Medal of the Arts, Certificate, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Notes, circa 1960s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Correspondence, circa 1932-2010; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 1.2 Linear feet Boxes 1-2, Oversize 7
  Correspondence is with friends, colleagues, and organizations. Correspondents include Isabel Bishop, Paul Cadmus, Walter Bachinski, William Christopher, Otto Dix, Jared and Margaret French, Ralph Ginzburg, Xavier Gonzalez, Robert Isaacson, Edward Laning, Lincoln Kirstein, Lee Nordness, Bernard Perlin, Joan Peterson, Theodore Stamos, Bridget Tichenor, and others. Also included are family correspondence and correspondence regarding the Estate of William Christopher.
  - Addison Gallery of American Art, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, circa 1994-2001; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 7)
  - Paul Cadmus, circa 1948-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Estate of William Christopher, circa 1960-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bridget Bate Tichenor, circa 1973-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - To William Chistopher, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - From G. Tooker's Mother, circa 1949-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, 1932-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence, 1956-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 46-47)
  - Correspondence, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4-6)
  - Correspondence, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
  - Correspondence, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1996-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1999-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 2005-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23-26)
  - Unsent Correspondence, circa 1940s-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Project Files, circa 1935-1968; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 0.3 Linear feet Boxes 2-3, 6
  Project files document Tooker's commissions including the set and costume design for Gian-Carlo Menotti's opera The Saint of Bleecker Street and Tooker's participation in the selection of candidates for the Vestris Prize for Choreography. Files contain correspondence, business documents, printed ephemera, sketches, photographs, three volumes of vocal scores, and textile samples.
  - Agreements, Art Students' League (New York, N.Y.), 1965-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Commission, NASA, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Commission, The Saint of Bleecker Street, 1953-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30-35)
    (Includes photographs, sketches, and vocal scores)
  - Set Design Agreement, The Saint of Bleeker Street, Teatro alla Scala, Milan, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Vocal Scores, The Saint of Bleecker Street, 1953-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
  - Committee of Judges for the Vestris Prize, 1966-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
  - Miscellaneous Projects, 1939-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Textile samples, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Gallery Records, circa 1960-2009; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; .3 Linear feet Box 3
  Gallery records include business correspondence and consignments with various key galleries in Tooker's career spanning the 1960s to the end of his career including D.C. Moore Gallery, Marisa Del Re Gallery, and Durlacher Bros..
  - D.C. Moore Gallery, circa 1996-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Durlacher Bros., 1966-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Frank K.M. Rehn, Inc. American Paintings, 1968-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - George Dix Paintings and Drawings, 1968-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Marisa Del Re Gallery, circa 1982-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Business Documents, 1960-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Inventory with Provenance, circa 1970-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Peintures Ltd. (William Christopher), 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Exhibition Records, circa 1967-2009; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; .3 Linear feet Box 3
  Exhibition records include documents regarding the organization of several select exhibition in Tooker's career including an early retrospective at the Fine Arts Museums of San Francisco (1974) and a later traveling retrospective from 2008-2009.
  - Dartmouth College, Hopkins Center Art Galleries (Summer 1967), Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Fine Arts Museums of San Francisco, Retrospective (1974), circa 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - George Tooker: Paintings and Working Drawings, University of Richmond Marsh Gallery (Jul.-Sep. 1989), Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Cadmus, French, and Tooker: The Early Years, Whitney Museum of American Art at Philip Morris (Mar.-May 1990), circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Reality and Dream: The Art of George Tooker, The Ogunquit Museum of American Art (Aug.-Sep. 1996), Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Traveling Retrospective, National Academy of Art (Oct. 2008-Jan. 2009), 2007-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Traveling Retrospective, Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts (Jan.-Apr. 2009), 2006-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Traveling Retrospective, Guest Book, circa 2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Printed Material, circa 1851-2010; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet Boxes 3, 5
  Printed material consists of invitations, press releases, news clippings and exhibition catalogs documenting the careers of both George Tooker and William Christopher.
  - Book, Conversations with Artists by Selden Rodman, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Book, The Floral Wreath: An Offering of Friendship, 1851; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Invitations and Announcements, circa 1942-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Magazines and Journals, 1954-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - News Clippings, circa 1956-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26-27)
  - News Clippings, circa 1980s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Press Releases, 1946; 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Scrapbooks, 1945-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - William Christopher Invitations and Announcements, circa 1952-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - William Christopher Exhibition Catalogs, circa 1957-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - William Christopher News Clippings, circa 1952-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - William Christopher Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1965-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Commercial Printing Featuring George Tooker Reproductions, 1987, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Artwork and Sketchbook, circa 1932-2009; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 0.7 Linear feet Boxes 3, 5, 8
  Artwork includes numerous sketchbooks, loose drawings, and sketches from Tooker's studies at the Art Students' League in the mid 1940s, in addition to an early ex-libris print created by Tooker in his youth. Also included is a sketchbook by William Christopher. Also included is a study for the 1950 painting The Subway, in the collection of the Whitney Museum of American Art.
  - Study for The Subway,(Watercolor and Pencil on Board), circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Painting, Oil on Board, circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Drawings and Sketches, Reginald Marsh's Class, Art Students' League, 1944-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35-41)
  - Drawings and Sketches, Reginald Marsh's Class, Art Students' League (Pen and Watercolor on Paper), circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 2-4)
  - Drawings and Sketches, Reginald Marsh's Class, Art Students' League (Charcoal on Paper), circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Sketchbook, Reginald Marsh's Class, Art Students' League, circa 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Sketchbooks, Reginald Marsh's Class, Art Students' League, circa 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 6-10)
  - Sketchbooks, Student Work, circa 1941-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Sketchbooks, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Ex Libris by George Tooker, 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - William Christopher Sketchbook, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Copies of Paul Cadmus Study of Francisco, by Ernest M. and Philip, circa 2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Photographs, circa 1900-2010; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 1.1 Linear feet Boxes 4-5, 8
  Photographic materials depict Tooker's family life as well as his early artistic collaborations depicted in a number of black and white photographs taken by George Platt Lynes and PaJaMa in the mid to late 1940s. A majority of the photographs depict artists and friends, among them: George Tooker and his companion William Christopher, Paul Cadmus, Jared and Margaret French, Lincoln and Fidelma Kirstein, Glenway Wescott, Monroe Wheeler, and Bridget Tichenor. Other photographs are of Tooker building his home, gardening, and working in his studio in Hartland, Vermont. Also included are installation views from the exhibition Painting in the United States (1949) at the Carnegie Institute in Pennsylvania. There are also a fair amount of photographs, transparencies, slides and negatives documenting artwork from both the studios of George Tooker and his late partner William Christopher.
  - G. Tooker Childhood Photographs, circa 1920-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - G. Tooker Childhood Photographs, circa 1921-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - G. Tooker Family Photographs, Reprints, circa 1900-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Friends and Family, circa 1945-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of George Tooker, Hartland, Vermont, circa 1957-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
    (Includes studio views)
  - Photograph of George Tooker, Hartland, Vermont, circa 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Studio and Home in Hartland, Vermont, circa 1958-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
  - Photographs by PaJaMa, Nantucket, Massachusetts, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Photographs by PaJaMa, Provincetown, Massachusetts, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)